Brooke Walters, Data Scientist

Intellectually curious, creative, and systematic analytics professional with 8+ years' experience in market research and insights analysis. Effective at building influential relationships and delivering impactful insights to executives. Currently pursuing a M.S. in Data Science & Analytics.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Data Scientist, PillarFour Media

Grand Rapids, MI | October 2022 - current

- Supported the integration of Shiny and Flexdashboard interfaces into data reporting and analytics processes, aiming to increase efficiency and improve the accessibility of insights for decision-making.
- Updated and maintained key data pipeline resources, including dashboards and reports, ensuring accurate and up-to-date information for stakeholders.
- Assisted in the monitoring and updating of machine learning models, participating in exploratory analysis for new projects.
- Contributed to ad-hoc modeling projects, enhancing cross-functional collaboration by participating in proactive code reviews with business teams. (This highlights your collaborative efforts and broader understanding of the business.)

Senior Insights Analyst, Corewell Health

Grand Rapids, MI | October 2022 - October 2023

- · Collected, transformed, and quantified statistically significant market research results, cutting the feedback loop from months to minutes. Developed real-time ticketing solution for patient concerns, streamlining operations and response times.
- Deployed natural language processing (NLP) tools for in-depth consumer sentiment analysis and thematic categorization. Embedded results into dynamic dashboards accessed daily by operations, resulting in the validation of special projects and exceeding consumer experience benchmark goals.
- Utilized R programming language and Tableau to aggregate and analyze population health data and market trends, translating findings into actionable insights for competitive intelligence. Analysis informed strategic decisions, enabling teams to proactively identify and capitalize on growth opportunities.

Market Research & Insights Analyst, Spectrum Reach

Grand Rapids, MI | January 2016 - October 2022

- Analyzed consumer behavior and communicated key findings through data visualizations, presentations, and written summaries, directly contributed to an increase of \$3.4 million in ad revenue
- Initiated the adoption of Salesforce groups to streamline communication across time zones, curating a repository of best practices, and increased accessibility to insights with cross-functional partners.
- Curated and distributed daily newsletters, updating local sales teams across the U.S. on emerging multiplatform advertising trends bolstering Spectrum Reach's reputation as a knowledgeable leader in audience-based multiscreen advertising solutions.

CONTACT



Brooke.Melissa.Walters@gmail.com



616-780-9024



linkedin.com/in/bmwlters/



brookemwalters.github.io/Collection/

EDUCATION

Grand Valley State University

Data Science and Analytics, M.S (current) **GPA 3.95**

Grand Valley State University

Advertising and Public Relations, B.S. Minor, Business

SKILLS

Programming Languages: R, SQL Python

Predictive Modeling: TidyModels, Linear and Logistic Regression

Project Management: Collaborative Problem Solving, Salesforce, GitHub, Notion

Business Acumen: Primary Market Research, Presentations, Reporting, Stakeholder Engagement

Data Manipulation and Analysis: Data Cleaning, Data Mining, Data Aggregation

Data Visualization: Tableau, Microsoft

Office Suite, Neustar, rShiny